VARNA VINCENT

394 Boynton Ave, Apt B-10, San Jose, CA 95051

6692046244, varnamvmv@gmail.com

SUMMARY

An ace web developer with four years experience in extensive web and mobile application development in vacation rental, product distribution and healthcare domains. Known for strong technical, analytical and organizational abilities. Excellent team player with strong work ethic and personal integrity. Strong technical expertise in the latest web and mobile technologies and comfortable following the agile practices.

SKILLS

- **Strong:** Core Java, Javascript
- Intermediate: Git, VueJs, PHP, Laravel, HTML5, Ionic framework, Apache Camel, REST, SOAP Webservices, MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres, AngularJS, XML, XSLT, AJAX
- **Familiar:** Spring, Oracle, Maven

SIDE PROJECTS

- My Website
- <u>Number Sense Game</u> An interactive game to help you visualize numbers and develop your number sense.

EXPERIENCE

Nibodha Technologies, Infopark, Kakkanad (2015 - 2016)

Care Services [May 2016 – July 2016]

- Mobile app that helps the general practitioner to find nearby community services for patients
- Tools used: AngularJs, Ionic Framework, Firebase, Git

Always On Vacation [January 2016 – May 2016]

- Contributed to developing a framework for bulk data processing Databridge
- Exposed APIs to various distributors and integrated modules from many vacation rental property suppliers
- Tools used: Core Java, Maven, Apache Camel, Jenkins, Spring, MongoDB, MySql, Oracle, Git

Mobile Insight [October 2015 – December 2015]

- Developed a highly scalable messaging module
- Tools used: Core Java, Maven, Git, Jenkins, Spring

SOS [March 2015 – September 2015]

- Involved in a team of two, in developing a responsive website for the administrator, a tablet app for the SWAT team and authorities of an organization and a cross-platform mobile app for the employees in an organization; to be used in the event of a catastrophe.
- Tools used: Angularis, javascript, Parse db, Ionic framework, Bootstrap, Grunt, Yeoman

Zerone Consulting Pvt. Ltd., Infopark, Kakkanad (2012 - 2015)

Software Engineer - Level 3

HealthFabric - SugarCRM Integration [November 2014 – March 2015]

- Assisted in the development of an application to integrate HealthFabric, a healthcare module and SugarCRM, a customer relationship management system.
- Have moderate expertise in development of the switchyard application routing web services between HealthFabric and SugarCRM.
- Tools Used: Switchyard, JBOSS, REST, SOAP webservices, Core Java, Maven

HealthFabric - Tablet [November 2014 – March 2015]

- HealthFabric is a tablet based solution, allowing patients to record their own health and social care information.
- Part of the development team of the phonegap application for HealthFabric
- Tools Used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Ajax, SQLite DB

Acer Web Development [May 2013 – October 2014]

- Led a team of 3 engineers to enhance ACER's Australian site for their distributers and retailers.
- Involved in the development of additional modules for their budget forecasting, special pricing for bulk demands and gross price calculations.
- Involved in the enhancement of existing modules to facilitate & collaborate the Claim process between Acer's customers and the various business units within Acer.
- Tools used: Java, Servlets, Spring 2.0, XML, XSLT, Oracle db, Maven, JBOSS server, HTML, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX

Data Scrapper [August 2012 – December 2012]

- Involved in a team of five, in extracting data from various healthcare congress meeting abstracts.
- Tools used: Microsoft Excel 2013, VBA, Macro

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

• Currently developing a website for a non profit organization in Arizona, <u>Collaborating for a Cause</u> using PHP, Laravel, Postgres SQL.

EDUCATION

TocH Institute of Science and Technology, Arakkunnam

BTech in Computer Science and Engineering, 2008-2012.

MES Udyogamandal School, Eloor

Indian School Certificate Examination (ISC – Std XII).

Mount Tabor Residential Central School, Kalamassery

Indian Council of Secondary Education(ICSE – Std X).

EXTRA CURRICULAR

- Anchor/Comperer at technical conferences hosted by MobConf.
- Active member of MobConf Technical Community.
- Co-ordinator of events at Nibodha Technologies and Zerone Consulting.
- Member of Entertainment Committee at Zerone Consulting.